SEBASTIEN SKAWSKI

Longueuil, QC | 514-883-5977 | sebastien.skawski@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Determined and detail-oriented **Professional** with an advanced academic background in **International Development** & **Humanitarian Action Management** and over 2 years of analyzing and interpreting data for the Government of Canada. Recognized as an analytical problem solver who meticulously gathers and evaluates complex data to gain insight and offer strategic guidance. Confident communicator who builds strong working relationships, translates complicated information into meaningful terms, and effectively collaborates with diverse stakeholders on a daily basis.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Data Analysis & Management
- Client Relations & Engagement
- Research & Policy Evaluation
- Customer Service & Support
- Reporting & Documentation
- Issue Investigation & Resolution
- Interpersonal Communication
- Leadership & Team Building
- Multitasking & Prioritization

Languages: French (native) | English (advanced) | Spanish (intermediate) | Persian (basic) | Mandarin (basic)

Technical Skills: Microsoft Office Suite | Adobe Photoshop | Video Editing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

<u>Service Canada</u> – Montreal, QC Citizen Services Officer (PM-01)

2020 to Present

- Accountable for answering client questions regarding Service Canada programs including Employment Insurance (EI), Old Age Security (OAS), Canada Pension Plan (CPP), and the Canada Emergency Response Benefit (CERB)
- Investigate and address inquiries for up to 45 clients per day and offer guidance and referrals to external resources
- Analyze complex files and interpret relevant laws and policies to determine the best course of action for clients
- Collect biometric data from clients applying to various Immigration, Refugees & Citizenship Canada services
- Process requests to update and alter database information related to social insurance numbers (SIN), EI, and OAS
- Review and authenticate personal documentation, identify potential fraud, and issue new SINs to eligible clients Key Achievements:
- ✓ Received the peer-nominated Tech Award for serving as the go-to office resource for IT-related problems
- ✓ Earned glowing feedback from several clients for going above and beyond customer service expectations

<u>Immigration, Refugees & Citizenship Canada (IRCC)</u> – Montreal, QC Client Support Agent (CR-05)

2019 to 2020

- Provided bilingual support to up to 50 callers per day by addressing questions regarding the immigration process
- Built instant rapports with clients to understand needs and offer knowledgeable recommendations and advice
- Delivered expert customer service to French and English clients by resolving all issues in a timely manner
- Researched applications for citizenship and immigration services in the Global Case Management System (GCMS) Key Achievements:
- ✓ Played a key role in helping a client avoid deportation by studying Canada's international visa agreements with Venezuela and demonstrating to the Immigration Officer that they made a mistake in their decision
- ✓ Successfully assisted family members affected by the Ukraine International Airlines flight PS752 disaster with navigating and expediting the immigration process during the stressful and traumatic period
- ✓ Co-developed and presented a proposal to streamline and enhance the training program for new employees
- ✓ Completed the training program to become a Universal Agent with knowledge of the entire immigration program
- ✓ Deployed to the Citizen Services Officer role for routinely exceeding all performance expectations at the IRCC

SEBASTIEN SKAWSKI

Longueuil, QC | 514-883-5977 | sebastien.skawski@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Doors & Windows Ultra - Montreal, QC & Toronto, ON

2017 to 2019

Carpenter

- Performed a variety of carpentry duties during renovation and installation projects at residential buildings
- Coordinated with team members to confirm all project specifications were achieved within client deadlines

<u>Casa Chill Inn</u> – Atacames, Ecuador

2016

Front Desk Staff

- Greeted new guests, facilitated hostel tours, and cleaned and maintained the front desk and common areas
- Received incoming messages, prepared customer correspondence, and participated in social activities

Hotel Cielo Azul - Atacames, Ecuador

ESL Teacher

2016

- Devised and delivered English language lessons, activities, and exercises to groups of 8 students
- Produced and distributed audio recordings for students to practice their English speaking abilities

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Laval University – Laval, QC

In Progress

DESS in International Development & Humanitarian Action Management

University of Quebec à Montreal (UQÀM) – Montreal, QC

2018

BA in Political Science & International Relations

• Authored a research paper on the rise of China as a global power in 2050 within the context of international relations theory by conducting an in-depth literature review and analysis of contemporary geo-political trends

Relevant Coursework: Elements of Statistics for Human Sciences | Foundation of Political Analysis | International Relations Theory | Politics & The Economy | Public Administration | Government Decision-Making & Central Bodies

<u>Public Service Commission of Canada</u> – Montreal, QC Second Langue Evaluation (SLE) in English (CCC)

2019